INFO

Address:

Ingolstadt, Germany

Phone:

+49 157 39689677

Email:

sahoo.bimalesh@gmail.com

Portfolio:

https://sahoobimalesh.in

Behance:

behance.net/bimaleshsahoo

SKILLS

UX Research, Wireframing
UI Design, Prototyping, User
Personas, Interaction Design
Design Thinking, Data Viz
Responsive Web Design
Augmented Reality, Mobile
Design, Agile Methodology

TOOLS

Sketch, Adobe XD, Axure RP Photoshop, Illustrator, Figma Protopie, After Effects Premiere Pro, Miro

EDUCATION

M.Sc

User Experience Design

Technische Hochschule Ingolstadt Ingolstadt, Germany 2020 - 2022

B.Tech

Electronics & Communication

Sikkim Manipal Inst of Tech Gangtok, India 2012 - 2016

BIMALESH SAHOO

User Experience Designer

PROFILE

A Creative Designer with 5 years of professional experience working in the field of User Experience Design. Original and clever with the ability to work with design and development teams. Better understanding of requirements, business goals, Apple and Google design guidelines, branding documents and converting prepared solutions into innovative wireframes by creating work flows and interactive prototyping designs.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Siemens Healthineers, Working Student

Ingolstadt, Germany

Oct 2021 - present

- Analyse the user surveys results of physicians & technologists who use CT-Scan device and design a better interaction for them.
- Design the interaction of the digital scan output in iPads and Desktops.

Dassault Systèmes, User Experience Designer

Pune, India

Oct 2019 - Nov 2020

- Involved in define and design of Document Management Application for ENOVIA on the 3DEXPERIENCE Platform.
- Completed user research to identify opportunities for improving web presence.
- Facilitated clients' product vision by researching, sketching, prototyping.
- Designed UI elements and tools such as navigation menus, search boxes, tabs and widgets for digital components.

Wipro Limited, User Experience Designer

Pune, India

July 2016 - Oct 2019

- Designed and built advanced applications for the iPhone, iPads, Web platform.
- Collaboration with functional teams to define, design and ship new features.
- Have got a great exposure with clients and customers by working with them.
- Worked in a fast paced, agile and in an ownership and results oriented culture.
- Close interaction with the development teams to get the best out of designs.
- Ability to handle and lead a team ensuring deliverables within stipulated time.

AWARDS



Winner of German UPA UX Challenge 2021, 3rd Place